# KRISNA GUPTA

# PhD Candidate in Economics at The Australian National University (ANU)

At Crawford School of Public policy under supervision of Arianto Patunru, My thesis is about the impact of trade and investment policies to Indonesian firms. I help tutor some courses in The ANU. I am also an associate researcher at CIPS Indonesia



## **EDUCATION**

Universitas Indonesia

M.S.E. in Economics

Oppok, Indonesia

2014

2014

**VU University Amsterdam** 

M.Sc. in Economics

• Amsterdam. The Netherlands



#### **Book**

• Gupta, Krisna and Enny Mardjono (2021). Indonesia Emas Berkelanjutan 2045: Kumpulan Pemikiran Pelajar Indonesia Sedunia Seri 01 Ekonomi. Jakarta: LIPI Press. ISBN: 978-602-496-208-1

#### **Journal Article**

- Gupta, Krisna. (2022). The Heterogenous Impact of Tariff and NTM on Total Factor Productivity of Indonesian Firms. Bulletin of **Indonesian Economic Studies**
- Gupta, Krisna, (2021). The Importance of Financial Liberalisation for Economic Growth: The Case of Indonesia. Bulletin of Indonesian Economic Studies, 57:2, 175-201, DOI: 10.1080/00074918.2020.1747596

## **Book Chapter**

 Gupta, Krisna (2020). "Industri 4.0 Sebagai Solusi Daya Saing Industri Indonesia?". In Denny Irawan, Wasisto Raharjo Jati, Oscar Karnalim, Asrul Sidiq (ed.), Mewujudkan Indonesia 4.0: Kumpulan Pemikiran Pelajar Indonesia di Australia. Jakarta: Yayasan Pustaka Obor Indonesia. ISBN: 978-602-433-918-0

#### **Book Review**

• Gupta, Krisna. (2020). "World Trade Evolution: Growth, Productivity and Employment - edited by Lili Yan Ing and Miaojie Yu". Asian-Pacific Economic Literature. https://doi.org/DOI:10.1111/apel.12291

#### **Proceedings**

• Gupta, Krisna, Bayu Sutjiatmo and Muhammad Kurniawan. 2019. "How Trump's steel and aluminium tariff shapes future world trade". in Abdullah, Widiaty and Abdullah (eds). Global Competitiveness: Business Transformation in the Digital Era. London: Routledge.

# CONTACT INFO

krisna.or.id

For more information, please contact me via email.

#### **SKILLS**

Trained in economics with heavy use of various types of panel data regressions to evaluate policies

Have a long exposure with STATA, but recently learning R and Python for econometrics

Experience in running structural model (e.g. GTAP) using **GEMPACK** software

> This resume was made with the R package pagedown.

> > Last updated on 2022-02-03.

### Popular Publications / Oped

- Gupta, Krisna and Deasy Pane. 2021. "Restrictive regulations on foreign trade may hurt economy". *The Jakarta Post.*
- Gupta, Krisna and Wishnu Mahraddika. 2021. "Mengapa tren kendaraan listrik adalah momentum transformasi industri otomotif Indonesia". *The Conversation Indonesia*.
- Pasaribu, Donny and Krisna Gupta. 2020. "Will IA-CEPA be the boost to Australia-Indonesia relations leaders are banking on?". *Indonesia At Melbourne*.
- Patunru, Arianto and Krisna Gupta. 2020. "Indonesia's PPE export ban backfires". East Asia Forum.

# **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

#### Lecturer at Politeknik APP Jakarta

• Business Statistics (2016-2017)

# Tutor at Australian National University

- POLS3025 Contemporary Political Analysis, using STATA in political analyses (2017)
- ECON3101 Microeconomics 3 (2018-2021)
- ECON3102 Macroeconomics 3 (2021)
- ECON2102 Macroeconomics 2 (2019)
- EMET3008 Applied Macro and Financial Econometrics (2020)

#### Teaching Assistant at Universitas Indonesia

- Macroeconomics 2 (2016)
- Microeconomics 2 (2015)

# **PRIZES**

2012 • VU Fellowship Programme (VUFP)

A scholarship given by VU for my master degree

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

## 2017 • Australia Awards Indonesia (AAI)

A scholarship from the Australian government to conduct a study in Australia.

Ocanberra, Australia

#### 2019 • Hadi Soesastro Prize (HSP)

Awarded by the Australian government to be used for research in Indonesian development

Ocanberra, Australia